Guide to the Kingman Brewster, Jr., President of Yale University, Inauguration Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Kingman Brewster, Jr., president of Yale University, inauguration records
1959-1964
RU 13
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(10 boxes)
Kingman Brewster, Jr., was inaugurated the seventeenth president of Yale University on 11 April 1964. The records document the planning and management of the inauguration and include press materials, such as clippings, releases, and the Yale Daily News special inauguration edition; invitations, tickets, and the ceremony program; congratulation messages; invitation and attendance lists; and records detailing ceremonial order and logistics. The records also include congratulation messages on Brewster's appointment as Yale University Provost in 1959.
Yale University. President's Office
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 2-A (YRG 2-A), Records of the President.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Office of the President, 1976 and 1978.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
Kingman Brewster, Jr., was inaugurated the seventeenth president of Yale University on 11 April 1964. The records document the planning and management of the inauguration and include press materials, such as clippings, releases, and the Yale Daily News special inauguration edition; invitations, tickets, and the ceremony program; congratulation messages; invitation and attendance lists; and records detailing ceremonial order and logistics. The records also include congratulation messages on Brewster's appointment as Yale University Provost in 1959.
College presidents -- Inauguration; Brewster, Kingman, Jr., 1919-1988; Yale University -- Presidents; Yale University. President's Office
- Records concerning the inauguration of Kingman Brewster, Jr., as president of Yale University, 1959-1964; Original Accession
  - 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
  - 1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Attendance and invitation lists, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Ball, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Biography of Kingman Brewster, Jr., Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Budget [and set-up], 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - Congratulations on Kingman Brewster, Jr.'s, appointment as provost
    - 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Congratulations [inaugural], 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Congratulations, greetings, and speech requests, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
  - Congratulations on the presidency
    - A-B, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - C-L, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 26-30)
    - M-Z, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 31-35)
  - Congratulations on the presidency from Yale faculty and staff, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Delegates, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Friday discussions and dinners, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Housing, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 39-40)
  - Inaugural address (1964 Apr 11), 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Invitation list, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Meals
    - 1964 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - 1964 (Box 7, Folder 44-45)
  - Personal guest list, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Press
    - 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Press kit, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Press releases, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Program of the ceremony, luncheon program, and invitation (Apr 11), 1964 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Samples of tickets, programs, and invitations to small functions (Apr 11), 1964 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Special guests, 1963-1964 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Oversize: Invitation list, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 53-56)
- Printing samples from the inauguration of Kingman Brewster, circa 1964; Accession 19ND-A-150
  - Printing samples from the inauguration of Kingman Brewster, circa 1964 (Box 1)
- Motion picture film of Brewster inauguration, Accession 2010-A-042
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - Motion picture film of Brewster inauguration, 1964; 1 film reel (35mm, color) (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    No sound